Vinoth Kumar Pandiyan, Senior Software Engineer

 $760408, Singapore, +65\,80313051, vinothkumar. 10 @outlook.com$

Date of birth	10-08-1992 Na	tionality	Indian
LINKS	Website, Linkedin		
PROFILE	Senior Software Engineer with 7 years of experience. Improve performance and enhance coding standards in the organization. Able to deliver releases on time and ability to effectively self-manage during independent project and collaborate as part of a productive team.		
EMPLOYMENT HISTORY			
Jan 2023 — Present	Senior Software Engineer - Resear	ch, Digify	Singapore
	Working closely with the product strategy team to bring the next thing for Digify		
Sep 2020 — Jan 2023	Senior Software Engineer (Front-	End Lead) , Digify	Singapore
	 Improve error catching by setting internal standards, and documentation and improve release bugs by 80%. Improved document render web components meant the user's wait is reduced to half, improving the overall performance initial page load. Added i18n to the web app and improved user coverage to 90%. Learn, collaborate, and share with other developers to ensure the product is released on time and of high quality. Worked on various Proof-of-Concept applications using flutter and electron. Revamped the angular app from version 1.7 to newer angular with improved overall app performance. Developed a concept react application for the legacy app before trying with angular 		
Sep 2015 — Aug 2020	Software Engineer, Digify		Singapore
	 Implemented user interface design and write front-end script for the Digify app Creating build scripts (gulp) for deployment. Developed and improved file viewer component which support more formats to viewed by user and file management functionalities. Develop and fix issues on the Android app. Developed a chrome extension, that integrates Digify's file-sharing feature into Gmail attachments. Documented and did internal testing for web application. 		
EDUCATION			
Jul 2014 — Aug 2015	Graduate Diploma in Systems Analysis, National University of Singapore		Singapore
Aug 2009 — Mar 2013	Bachelor of Engineering, Madras Institute of Technology Chennai		
	Major in Computer Science		
SKILLS	JavaScript, TypeScript, ES6+	Flutter/ Dart	
	HTML, CSS, Less, Sass	Git, Github	
	Angular	Agile, Scrum, Kanban	
	React	Test Driven Development	
		<u>.</u>	

LANGUAGES English Highly proficient Tamil Native speaker